選別の開始まで　あと３日
Fearsome monsters... Exotic creatures...
宮殿内では 傷の治療を終えた王が 今も休まずに軍儀を続けていた
Vast riches... Hidden treasures...
詰みだ。
Evil enclaves... Unexplored lands...
はぁ。 フゥ…。
The word "unknown" holds magic. And some incredible people are
drawn to that magic.
心身ともに もう限界が来ている
They are known...
恐らく次局か その次には　王が勝つ
...as Hunters!
休憩だ　半日後に再開する。
Those who win will join
the ranks of the Hunters.
はっ？ いえ　ワダすは　まだまだ！
Can't Win x And x Can't Lose
フラフラの貴様に勝っても 余の気が済まぬわ。
Nine applicants:
しっかり体調を戻せ。 腕の治療中も 決して　対局を止めなかった王が
Gon, Killua, Kurapika, Leorio, Pokkle, Bodoro, Gittarackur, Hanzo, and Hisoka, head to the Final Phase, having passed
the exam's Fourth Phase.
自ら前言を撤回した
Well, gentlemen.
この女…　危険だ
Did you get plenty of rest? This hotel is owned by the
Hunter Exam Selection Committee.
このままだと 厄介な存在になる
The place is all yours until the
battles have concluded.
んっ？
So only the last person standing passes?
んだば　お先に失礼すます。
No. One win is all you need to pass.
王が自らの言葉を翻したのも
The winners are removed from competition, while the losers continue up the bracket.
自身の信念を貫くため 万全の状態の 軍儀王をねじ伏せ
In other words, the person who
finishes at the top will not pass.
自身の実力を証明するため
Does everyone understand now?
私が今 この娘を始末してしまったら
So you're saying that only
one person will fail. Exactly.
彼女は　死によって神格化し 王の中で　決して 勝ち得ない存在となってしまう
And here is the bracket.
世界に君臨し
But some people, like #294 and #405, get five chances.
うわ！ あ！　あぁ…。
Why didn't you use a balanced bracket? A question that must be on everyone's mind.
んっ？
This bracket was assembled
based on your performances
ノヴさんのマンションから 宮殿に突入するのは　７人。
throughout the entire exam.
俺とシュート　ゴン　キルア メレオロン　イカルゴ
Those who performed better
received more chances.
そして　モラウの旦那。
That doesn't sound right.
ピトーの「円」の外側から やって来る会長は 俺達よりも数秒　突入が遅れる。
Can you explain how you
scored our performances?
俺達は護衛軍を 王から分散させる。
No! Why not?
先陣は　ゴン　キルア　イカルゴ。
Your scores are classified information.
いきなり　自陣の ど真ん中に出現する俺達に
So I can't tell you everything.
驚いた奴らが 本能的に取る行動は…。
But I can explain our methods. First, we consider three major criteria:
これを崩すのは簡単じゃねえな。 ん…
physical strength, mental strength, and overall impression.
そこで　この俺の出番だ。 うん。
For physical strength, we use
an aggregate of agility, flexibility, endurance, and perception.
さて　何か質問ある？ えっと… パームのことなんだけど
After all, you were strong enough to advance to the Final Phase.
今　どうしてるか 何とか分からないかな？
However, we are most concerned
with your overall impression.
死んでるか　潜んでるかの どっちかだよ。
This refers to any intangible factors
抜け出せたら連絡がある。
not previously mentioned.
ないのは　そういうことだろ？
You could consider this
万が一　奴らに見つかったら 自ら死を選ぶ。
an evaluation of your potential as a Hunter.
あいつは その覚悟で敵地に向かった。
And we also incorporate the
opinions of your peers.
こちらからパームの様子を 探ろうとするのは
That was our process.
彼女の覚悟を侮辱する行為だぞ。
Based on performance,
I should be ranked higher...
おい　言い過ぎだろ！ ゴンは　ただ パームが心配なだけでだな…。
Do I have less potential than Gon?
その心配が 低レベルだってんだよ！ んだと!? 帰って来た早々　このガキが！
The battle rules are quite simple. Weapons are allowed. No cheating.
仮に　パームが生きたまま 敵に捕まっていたとする。
If your opponent admits defeat, you win. However!
その場合 十中八九　作戦は敵にバレてる。 突入する俺達は
If you kill your opponent, you will be immediately disqualified.
「飛んで火に入る夏の虫」 ってとこか。
All remaining applicants will pass,
and the exam will end.
一瞬で全滅さ。
Are we clear?
そんな最悪の時のことを あれこれ考えるより 大事なのは パームを信じることだろ？
Then, we shall begin the exam's Final Phase.
まず　パームを最優先に 救い出すことを主張するんだよ。 で　どうやるかの方法は 人任せと来たもんだ。
The first match is Hanzo versus Gon. Please step forward.
その間にパームから 連絡あるかもしれないだろ。
I will serve as the referee.
ふん…　ニャるほど。
You were tailing me during the Fourth Phase. You noticed?
ここで　右辺に 活路を求めたら　どうだ？
I'm assuming that each applicant was
assigned an examiner for the Fourth Phase. Well, I'm sure everyone else noticed.
攻守両天秤で 中央に構えていたほうが
I had no idea. I obviously noticed.
ワダすは嫌ですた。
I thought it wasn't worth mentioning.
リスクを恐れずに 前に出るのも　時と場合です。
Y-Yeah... How was I supposed to notice that?
全て　それでは ワダすに迷いが生ずませんよ。
You have my thanks. My rank was higher because your
reports on me were accurate.
フン…　受けは性に合わんな。
Though the outcome was never in doubt! Y-Yes...
王様。 何だ？
Moving on, I have a question for you. What is it? We only win if our opponent
surrenders, correct?
あっ。 構わぬ　申せ。
It doesn't count if we knock them unconscious. No TKOs allowed, either.
国民大会が ２日後に迫ってまいりました。
Yes, that is correct.
ペイジンで処理する国民の数は
I see.
予定よりも　だいぶ増えましたが
This one could be difficult...
当日は　天候も良いようで 選別は問題なく行えます。
He looks tough, but we should be even
で？　要件のみ申せ。
in terms of strength and speed.
その後の統一までの スケジュールを
I can use my speed to keep on the
move until I get an opening.
できる限り早めたいのです。
Now then, it's time to begin.
はっ　つきましては 出発も選別終了直後とし…。
Get him, Gon!
二度　言わすな。 お前に任せると言っておるのだ。
How well can he do against Hanzo?
ククク…。
Begin!
とうとう お前まで追い出されたか。 まっ　王が勝つまでの辛抱だ。
Put some distance between us...
お前の読みじゃ あと数局ってとこだろ？
You must be confident in your legs.
いや…。 あっ？
You have my respect.
王は　確かに すさまじい速さで上達している しかし　彼女も進化している。
You did well for a kid.
すでに私が予想できるレベルを 超えている。 まっ　でも 王の勝ちは　時間の問題だろ？
Tsk. I could have easily dodged that attack.
だといいが…。 そうさ。 心配なんかいらねえよ。
Well, this would already be over
if it were a normal fight...
１００％　間違いなく 単独犯だニャ
You must feel terrible.
レオルを倒した男と同一人物
I hit you hard enough to make
your brain bounce around. Do you understand?
You have no chance against me.
統率された兵士は　奴の煙人形
Might as well give up now... No way...
文字通り　僕をけむに巻いた
Think about it.
僕の人形よりも 数は少ないけれど
If you surrender now, you'll still be in
decent shape for your next fight.
精度は　かなり上
There's no reason to be stubborn.
う… やりたいニャ。
Just surrender.
でも　ここから動けないニャ。
Never gonna happen!
ウニャ!!
Surrender.
その上で宮殿の周辺に 国民が大移動を開始する。
Gon! Don't be silly! You'll still have another chance! You should... Leorio!
大会前日に合わせて 気配を消せば
If you were in Gon's position,
would you surrender?
複数の敵が国民に紛れ込んで 王を狙うと
Hell, no!
護衛軍は考える。
That guy thinks he's hot stuff...
((自然と警戒は宮殿の外
Gon feels the same way!
周辺の国民に向けられる))
I know! I know that... But there isn't any other choice!
((そこへ　宮殿内の 「四次元マンション」から俺達が…))
You're contradicting yourself, but I understand how you feel!
今こそ　復讐の時！ ((３階の玉座の間で 選別の様子を見守る))
Yield this fight, Gon!
お前は「影」の末裔だな。 ((３階の玉座の間で 選別の様子を見守る))
It's suicide!
復讐のためだけに戦うがよい ((３階の玉座の間で 選別の様子を見守る)) 復讐のためだけに戦うがよい うっ…　何をした？ 本当に　そうだろうか？ うっ…　何をした？ クラピカ　死んじゃダメだよ！ 仲間なら絶対に死ぬな！ 本当に　そうだろうか？
Honestly, the chairman's nasty
streak is in a class all its own.
引っ掛かる　何か… クラピカ　死んじゃダメだよ！ 仲間なら絶対に死ぬな！
What do you mean?
映画を 見に来てくれた人には… 引っ掛かる　何か…
The applicants who've made it this far
映画を 見に来てくれた人には… 俺達ハンターの使命とルール
are unlikely to simply surrender.
「ハンター十ヶ条」が書かれた
True.
とっておきの 手ぬぐいをプレゼントするよ 劇場でしか 手に入らないアイテムだぞ
This goes beyond a "rather peculiar fight."
劇場へ急げ！
This system is just plain crazy.
８－７－２　「中将」。 ４－３－３　「弓」。
Hunter Vocabulary
全く間を置かず 急所　急所を攻めて来る
Hanzo
そういう局面に 手が導かれているからだ
It's been three hours.
それは　こやつが
There's nothing left for him to vomit.
余よりも　まだ数段 高みから打っている証し
Get up.
一体　どこまで強くなる？
Enough, already... I'm gonna kill you!
総帥様。
I'll fight you in his place!
ワダす…　変です。
If you can't take it, leave. It's only going to get worse.
止まらないんです。
And if you step in, Gon will be
the one disqualified!
素晴らしい手が
It's okay...
次々と　洪水みたいに 頭に　なだれ込んで来て。
Leorio.
ワダす もっと　もっと強くなれる！ 覚醒？
This is... nothing...
強くなるのは！
I-I can still fight...
少す　お休みをいただけませんか？
I'm going to break your arm.
自分から言いだすのは 初めてだな どうかしたのか？
I'm not joking around, so give up.
いえ　部屋で 書き留めておきたいんです。
Surrender.
浮かんで来る手を全部。 その目でか？ あっ！
Never!
これまでの棋譜を全て…
He really broke his arm.
分かった　休め。 はい。
There you go.
愚問だな
You can't use your left arm anymore.
名前…？ おい。
Kurapika, don't try to stop me.
名は？　何と申す。
If that bastard does anything else to Gon...
ワダすのですか？ 他に誰がいる？
Sorry, Gon, but I can't stop myself.
あっ　コ…　コムギです！
Me? Stop you?
コムギか…　うむ。
Don't worry.
総帥様は…
There is no chance of that happening.
総帥様のお名前は 何とおっしゃられるのですか？
I'm sure you're in too much pain to listen, but hear me out. I am descended from the shinobi,
a clan of covert agents.
余は…
From the day I was born, I was forced
何という？
to endure harsh training in order
to master the art of ninpo.
ピトー んっ。
For eighteen years, I have trained my body and
technique, without rest.
はっ　何でございましょう？ プフ。
By the time I was your age,
I had already killed a man.
はっ。 ユピー。 はっ。
Heh, that's nothing to brag about.
いかがなされましたか？ プフ。 はっ。
At this point in time,
you cannot defeat me in combat.
そう　お前はプフだ。
I'm trying to be nice. Admit defeat—
余の名前は何という？
Ow...
恐れながら申し上げます。
Damn it!
王は王です。 それ以外の何者でもなく 唯一無二の存在。
My head's cleared a bit, after all the
pain and that long explanation. Yes!
今は　さまざまな　まがいものが その名を無断で使っていますが
Gon, go! Kick him while he's down!
全て排除　抹殺いたします。 王といえば　世界中の誰もが
If you're eighteen, you're only
six years older than I am.
たった一人の存在を 思い浮かべるよう。
Besides, this isn't a battle
to see who's stronger.
王は称号。 称号は しょせん　冠で名前ではない。
It's to see who's willing to surrender first.
ユピーは　どうだ？
I let you kick me on purpose.
私には　荷が勝ち過ぎる問題。
Liar!
到底　答えを持ち得ること 叶いませぬ。
You don't understand... This isn't a warning.
ピトー。 ん。
It's an ultimatum.
やはり　王　ご自身のお気持ちが 一番大事でございます。
Was it too hard for you to understand?
王　ご自身が最も ふさわしいと思われる名を
Then I'll make it easier for you.
付けられるのが　よろしいかと。 ふむ　まぁ　よいわ。
I'll cut off your legs, so that they can't be reattached.
お名前は 選別の後でも遅くはありません。 まずは　明日。
A permanent injury should
help to wake you up.
滞りなく　作業を完了させることが 先決でございます。
But first, I'll ask you once more. Surrender.
気掛かりが　おありならば 私めらに。
I won't accept that!
われわれは そのために　ここにいます。 コムギの全身が光に包まれていた。 コムギ？
I don't want my legs cut off, but I don't want to surrender.
アカズの女だ。
So let's find a different way to fight!
あのような者の名前を
Hey... Do you understand
your own situation?!
覚醒したのだ。
Excuse me.
コムギは 飛躍的に強くなるだろう。
You don't get to make demands!
軍儀のみの話だがな。 ピトー。 はっ。
Are you trying to insult me?! I'm seriously gonna cut off your legs!
もしも　コムギを今回の
But I still will not surrender.
明日やる方法で選別していたら どうなっていた？ 死んでますね。
Besides, if you do that,
I'll bleed to death.
あくまで選別は　兵士たりうる 肉体と精神の持ち主を
He'll be disqualified if that happens, right?
選ぶためのやり方ですから。
Oh, yes.
生き残るのは　戦闘能力が 極めて高い者だけです。
See? Neither of us wants that to happen. So let's think of a better way.
コムギと出会って
I think he's okay now.
強さにも　いろいろあると学んだ。
Gon's taken control.
例えば　ここへ来る途中　余は…。
He's so self-centered...
王　どうか… どうか　おやめください
But he's succeeded in convincing
Hanzo and the rest of us.
子供を殺した。
Honestly...
王！ 決して言ってはいけません！
What is this? The situation hasn't changed.
あの子供が　もしかしたら。
Gon hasn't gotten stronger than his opponent.
似合わない！ ふさわしくない！
His arm is still broken!
ある分野で余を凌駕する才を 目覚めさせていたかもしれぬ。 絶対の王が…！
So why is the brutal
atmosphere from before
その芽を　余は摘んだ。
suddenly so much lighter?
余は… 王!!
You really don't get it...
フフフ…　ハハハ…。
If I kill you here, I need only try again next year. We are not on equal footing!
命を意味なく摘んだ。
He's right, Gon.
フッフッフッ…。 だとしたら　何という強さ！ 理不尽に現れ
You can try all you want
to talk your way out of this, but he's far stronger than you.
他のあまたある もろい強さを奪い
That isn't something you can
neutralize on the spot.
踏みにじり　壊す！
It all comes down to power.
私は　護衛軍失格です。 何で？
Why won't you concede?
It's easy to do. You can try again next year.
危うく王を侮辱するところでした。
You value your pride more
than your own life?!
王が自分の行いを 悔いているのではないかなどと
You're really willing to die for your pride?!
ええ　それだけのこと…。
I'm going to find my dad.
ん　でも　確かに
Your dad?
あの娘が来てから 王は　少し変わったニャ。
My dad is a Hunter.
ええ…　それは　事実。 王にとって　邪魔なら あの小娘　殺ればいいじゃねえか。
So I'm going to become a Hunter
and find him!
あ…　私が　あなたと 同じ思考レベルだったなんて…。
I believe that I'll find him one day...
余の力こそが この世の頂点にある 他の脆弱な強さなど
But I have a feeling that if I give up now, I'll never find him!
余の前では　何の意味もなさぬ
So I won't surrender.
コムギ　あの女とて同じこと たかが　軍儀 しょせん　盤上の遊び
If you don't yield, you'll die...
余が　ほんの少しなでれば ただの肉塊と化す
He defies reason.
余の気が変われば 今すぐにでも！
I give up. You win.
そうとも　余は一体 何をこだわっている？
I can't kill you.
詮ずるところ 選別の日が来るまでの暇つぶし
But I can't think of a way
to make you surrender.
選別は明日 もう　いいではないか
I'll take this loss and take my
chances in the next battle!
十分　楽しんだ　もう用なし
I can't accept that.
殺るか！　今すぐ!!
That's not fair!
うっ…。
Heh, I knew you would say that. You fool!
あっ…　ありがとうございます。
But I don't want to win like this! What am I supposed to do?
なぜ　助けを呼ばぬ!?
We can work together to figure it out!
ここも。 こっちも　血だらけではないか！ クソ！　何という… なんと　もろい生き物なのだ!! 早朝ですから。 あっ？
In other words, I've already
given up on this match, but you want me to try to win again, while helping to determine a way to
make you feel good about your victory!
ご迷惑をお掛けすては いけないと…。
Is that right? Uh-huh! You moron!
迷惑なことなど　何もない！
Hey, ref.
余は　一体…
I lose. Let's move on to the next match.
貴様は　大事な客だ。
Understood.
何を言っている？
But I want to tell the executive
committee something first.
たった今　こいつを 殺しに来たのではないのか!?
When he wakes up, he'll probably refuse his passing judgment.
うっ　うぅ…。
Because he's a stubborn boy, as we've seen.
なぜ　泣く!? なぜ　殺らぬ？ ずみばべん。
If Gon fails, wouldn't that make the
rest of our fights meaningless?
うっ…　うわん！
Gon's victory has been assured,
following Hanzo's concession.
何なのだ　この生き物は？ 余は　こいつを どうしたいのだ!?
The Final Phase, to determine
the single failing applicant, has only just begun.